

Phone: (778) 995-2659

E-Mail: tim.riopelle@gmail.com

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Unity Technologies** - Vancouver, BC

#### Senior VFX Artist

OCTOBER 2022 - FEBRUARY 2024

Prehistoric Planet Immersive (Vision Pro) - Apple

## ICON Creative Studio - Vancouver, BC

## Lead Lighting / Compositing Artist

MAY 2020 - AUGUST 2020

Monsters at Work - Pixar

## Lead Lighting / Compositing Artist

MARCH 2019 - MAY 2020

The Rocketeer- Disney Junior

## Bardel Entertainment Inc. - Vancouver, BC

### Lead Lighting / Compositing Artist

FEBRUARY 2018 - MARCH 2019

Dragon Prince - Wonderstorm / Netflix

### Lead Lighting / Compositing Artist

DECEMBER 2016 - FEBRUARY 2018

Dinotrux: Supercharged - Dreamworks Television

## Senior Lighting / Compositing Artist

MARCH 2015 - DECEMBER 2016

Dinotrux - Dreamworks Television

## Lighting / Compositing Artist

SEPTEMBER 2014 - MARCH 2015

Dinotrux - Dreamworks Television

### **ABOUT ME**

Technical CG artist with a focus on lighting, rendering, and compositing. Over 12 years of combined industry experience in VR (immersive), video games, television, streaming, and feature film, including multiple Emmy-nominated / winning productions.

Expert understanding of Maya (Render Setup / Arnold / VRay) and Nuke.
Proficiency in tool / UI scripting using Python.

Strong leadership, management, and problem-solving skills. Proven track record delivering professional quality content for high-profile, episodic productions. Great team player with excellent communication and mentoring skills. Teaching experience at the post-secondary level.

### **ADVANCED KNOWLEDGE:**

### **Lighting / Rendering / Compositing:**

- Maya
- Redshift
- Arnold
- VRay
- Nuke
- After Effects
- Photoshop

#### Technical:

- Python Tools (Maya / Nuke)
- User Interface Building

### **Production Management:**

- Shotgun
- Google Sheets

## Lighting / Compositing Artist

MAY - SEPTEMBER 2014

VeggieTales: In The House - Dreamworks Television

## Lighting / Compositing Artist

JANUARY – APRIL 2014

The Prophet - Feature Film

## **Compositing Artist**

MAY 2013 - JANUARY 2014

Lah-Lah's Adventures - Television

# Digital Alchemy - Vancouver, BC

Layout Artist

MAY - AUGUST 2012

## 3Plains Corporation - Vancouver, BC

CG Generalist

MAY – OCTOBER 2009

## Gekido Design - Vancouver, BC

Lead Artist

APRIL 2008 - MARCH 2009

## Wishbone X Creations - Vancouver, BC

CG Generalist

SEPTEMBER 2006 – DECEMBER 2007

Pro Wrestling X - Video Game

#### **INTERMEDIATE KNOWLEDGE:**

## **Modeling / Texturing:**

- Environment (Maya)
- Sculpting / Painting (Mudbox / Photoshop)

#### **Animation:**

• Character (Maya)

#### **TEACHING / MENTORING**

## Capilano University - North Vancouver, BC

Lab Supervisor (2D / 3D / VFX) AUGUST 2020 – JULY 2023

## LaSalle College International - Vancouver, BC

3D Modeling Instructor

MAY 2011 - AUGUST 2011

# Pacific Audio Visual Institute - Vancouver, BC

3D Animation Instructor

MAY 2010 - AUGUST 2010

#### **EDUCATION**

Capilano University - North Vancouver, BC

Credits Towards Digital Visual Effects Diploma

SEPTEMBER 2012 - MAY 2013

Pacific Audio Visual Institute - Vancouver, BC

Certificate in Animation & Game Design

SEPTEMBER 2005 - SEPTEMBER 2006

**University of Ottawa** - Ottawa, Ontario

Credits Towards Geography / Geomatics & Spatial Analysis Degree

SEPTEMBER 2002 - MAY 2005